Anthony Hien Vu

Full Stack Web Developer

Contact

Address

Wentworthville, NSW, 2145

Phone

0452668725

Email

avu120@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://avu120.github.io/por folio

GitHub

https://github.com/AVu120

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ir/anthony-hien-vu/

Skills

React

Excellent

Redux

Excellent

CSS/Modules/SASS/CSS-in-JS/CSS-in-HTML

Excellent

React Testing

Excellent

Full stack web developer with a strong preference for the frontend. I also have experience in QA and DevOps (I have 2 AWS associate certifications). Wherever I work, I'm always striving to upskill everyone in my team and learn from them too. Mentoring others and working as a cohesive team is very important to me.

Work History

2021-09 – now

Senior Front End Developer

Checkbox, Sydney, NSW

- Built new React UI with Redux in the primary B2B application.
- Implemented end to end automation tests (in CypressJS).
- Implemented migration from JavaScript to TypeScript on the frontend.
- Implemented mass-adoption of unit/integration tests on the frontend with Jest and React Testing Library.
- Trained/mentored junior engineers in React/frontend best practices (in areas like performance optimization and testing).
- Implemented agile team processes to reduce process ambiguity and improve consistency of team output.
- Influenced future product feature roadmap and technical architecture decisions.
- Added many new and old UI components to the Storybook.js design system.
- Built and modified Go (Golang) APIs.

2021-03 -2021-09

Full Stack Web Developer

oOh!media, Sydney, NSW

- Built new features into internal React & Redux applications.
- Gave comprehensive React training to mid & seniorlevel engineers.
- Built evergreen internal UI design system using Storybook.js.
- Built new features in Node Express.js/GraphQL servers.

Accessibility / WCAG Good Storybook (UI Design Excellent Figma (Design/Wireframe Good Excellent **AWS** Very Good **Building REST APIs Excellent Building GraphQL APIs SQL** Databases Very Good NoSQL Databases Very Good VueJS

- Built new features in python API servers.
- Made configuration changes in AWS services like SQS, Lambda and EC2.
- Made configuration changes to Concourse CICD pipelines.

2018-08 - Full Stack Web Developer

2021-02

Telstra, Sydney, NSW

- Performed full stack development of a Telstra enterprise web application with thousands of internal users utilizing the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack with redux. The primary feature of this application is a catalogue of charts displaying data from various sources. I built new features into this application every day. Some examples include allowing the users to query databases from within the application, automatically schedule user-written scripts against databases, set up monitoring & alarms, and many more. The application uses a microservices architecture and is deployed on AWS.
- Troubleshooted operational issues in AWS core services such as CloudWatch, EC2, ECR and DocumentDB.
- Containerized many applications using Docker.
- Configured NGINX reverse-proxies to forward requests to various servers/micro-services-in-dockercontainers.
- Wrote unit tests using Jest.js, Enzyme.js and React Testing Library.
- Set up CICD pipelines using Atlassian's Bamboo platform.
- Documented many APIs using Swagger/OpenAPI specification.

2017-02 - IT Consultant

2018-05

Good

KPMG, Sydney, NSW

- Implemented & configured Microsoft Dynamics 365
 ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) software for large multinational clients.
- Performed IT risk testing (audit).

Good

Languages

JavaScript

Excellen^a

TypeScript

Excellent

Python

Very Good

Go

Good

Java

Good

C++

Good

Education

2013-02 -2016-11

Bachelor of Science: Engineering

Sydney University - Sydney, NSW

Certifications

2021-07

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

2021-03

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Interests

- Web App Performance
- Time and Space Complexity of Algorithms and Data Structures
- Frontend & Backend System Architecture
- UX Design
- Responsive Design
- DevOps/Cloud/Serverless
- Mentoring
- Leadership
- Sustainability
- Al/Machine-Learning
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies, trends, and best practices.

Hobbies

- Ice Skating
- Cricket
- Hiking
- Running
- Reading
- Tech Meetups
- Traveling